Before we move on, I just want to tell you about the exception class hierarchy that exists in Java for a reason the reason is coming on for you in some time, but what are the different main exception classes in Java and what is the hierarchy, what that is for.
I will have a look in some time, but what is that, so you just have a look at it, see at the top of the hierarchy, we have the two able class.
So, again, this is in Java dot land, so that is Java dot land dot 12, right. And what happens is it has two immediate subclasses and exception.
Just give me a moment.
Just a moment, it seems to be stuck.
And this is not the exceptions that we have been discussing, these are not the errors that we are getting from day one, this is exception with a capital E error with a capital E two classes defined in the API, which are two subclasses, giant classes of the super class.
Right, it sits at the top of the hierarchy, and then with an exception, we have more subclasses like for example, some of them I'll just list them down for you.
We have, let's say, interrupted exception, right, we have a I/O exception, and I even has a subclass world, fine, not for exception, and then similarly, we have other subclasses.
Subclasses of exception, and then we have yet under the subclass that is runtime exception.
And runtime has its own subclasses like arithmetic exception.
Right, the one that you just saw in the last video, now you know it's a subclass of runtime, and runtime itself is a subclass of exception, which in turn is a subclass of throwable.
So you're seeing inheritance everywhere in Java, and just because we're talking about that, I'll just like to you to make a note of that is, there is a super class in Java, which sits at the top top of every class in Java.
That's the Java to the language object class, not the objects that we create a building, but object with the capital row in the Java to the language language.
That is the Java to the language object class is the super class of every class in Java, that means whether you do inheritance or not, you're indirectly working with inheritance at all times in the Java programming language.
So runtime has its own subclass of the MIDI exception, it has, for example, another exception class that is.
Index out of bounds exception, which has two subclasses that is.
Area index out of bounds exception and string.
Out of bounds exception, right, and you guys start when do we get an.
Area index out of one exception when you're trying to access an area index, which doesn't exist, remember that area area video, and if you try to access a string index, which doesn't exist, you get a string index out of.
string index out of an exception, these two are subclasses of index out of bounds exception.
Similarly, runtime exception has other subclasses like null pointer exception, this is an exception, which is thrown at the time when you try to access another reference, right, and then you have, for example, number format exception.
Which is again, a subclass of runtime exception and runtime exception, you now know is a subclass of exception, then on the other hand, with error, we have its own subclasses, like, for example, you have stack or flow it.
You have, for example, out of memory, x error, or exception.
You have a search in error.
And similarly, other subclasses now you know this is the general exception class hierarchy, why they've created it.
I have a model that in the next video, but for now, the sex dislike, this data is the Java, the lambda toy, the class is the super class of every exception class in Java, then it has two immediate subclasses exception on the left side, error on the right side, error with its own subclasses, exception with its own subclasses and runtime exception, which is a subclass of exception as its own subclasses, and even they have their own subclasses.